granta.com 2017-12-04

# Granta | The Magazine of New Writing

_Granta_ is committed to protecting your privacy. So that you fully understand your rights, we encourage you to read this privacy statement. Please direct questions regarding this statement to info@granta.com.

**Our privacy statement addresses the following questions:**

  * When does _Granta_ collect my personal information?
  * How is my personal information used?
  * Who does _Granta_ share information with?
  * What are my options to control the use of my personal information?
  * What else should I know about my privacy?
  * How do I accept this privacy statement?

_**When does**_ **Granta** _ **collect my personal information?**_

_Granta_ gathers information from members and visitors in three ways: voluntary registration / subscriptions, cookies and IP addresses. Here is some further information:

**Registration**  
When you create an account on granta.com or take out a subscription, we collect information that helps us identify you. The more information you provide, the better we can customize our services and your experience to suit your needs and preferences. At the initial registration screen we ask for your name, the region of the world you live in, your email address and your password. On occasion, we may also collect additional personal information if you choose to enter a contest, complete a survey form or sign up for our newsletter.

When you order from us, we also ask for your name, shipping address, telephone number and your credit card number and expiration date. This information is necessary for us to process your order.

_**We will not share any of this personal information without your consent.**_

**Cookies**  
We use cookies to store and track your preferences to provide you with a more personalized member experience. A cookie is a message sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Most Internet sites use cookies. You can set your browser preferences to reject all cookies, but this will prevent you from using most customized services, and you may have to repeatedly enter personal information in order to participate in various services or promotions. Cookies make your experience easier by saving your preferences and passwords. We also use cookies that contain no personal information at all. These cookies help us estimate our audience size and determine which areas of the _Granta_ website are the most popular.

For more information on how and why we use cookies, please see our cookie policy.

**IP address**  
An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer automatically when you use the Internet. When you visit a particular web page on the _Granta_ site, our server logs your IP address. We may log IP addresses for the purposes of systems administration, security, or to report information in aggregate form to our retail partners and advertisers (e.g., how many visitors logged in to our website) in a form that is not personally identifiable.

_**How is my personal information used?**_

**Customized look and feel**  
_Granta_ gathers the information noted above in order to provide you with a more personalized experience of the site. For instance, your personal information enables us to greet you when you return to our site and to provide you with specific information and services we think will be of interest to you. We review our members’ preferences, demographics, traffic patterns, and other information — as a whole — so that we can better understand who our audience is and what it wants.

_**Who does**_ **Granta** _ **share information with?**_

We will not disclose your personal information to third parties, except to the extent necessary to provide you with a requested service, or under circumstances required by law. We will disclose your personal information when we believe in good faith that any applicable law, regulation or legal process requires it, or where we believe disclosure is necessary to protect or enforce our rights or the rights of another member. We also disclose aggregated member statistics in order to describe our services and audience to prospective partners, advertisers and other third parties. However aggregate data is not traceable to you specifically.

_**What are my options to control the use of my personal information?**_

Most browsers can be configured to reject cookies or alert you when cookies are being sent. You may cancel your subscription to _Granta_ and/or request the removal of your personal information from our member records by sending an email to info@granta.com. We will send an email to confirm your request. After you respond, we will remove your information from our database. Residual information may remain in our archives and records, but this information will not be used for a commercial purpose. We reserve the right to maintain information on registered members who have violated our terms and conditions, or who have had their access to _Granta_ blocked, in order to detect repeat offenders.

_**What else should I know about my privacy?**_

You should be aware that if you voluntarily disclose personal information online in a public area, that information might be collected and used by others. We do not control the actions of our visitors and registered members. If you disclose personal information on our Facebook or Twitter accounts, or any other publicly accessible place on or associated with the _Granta_ site, you do so at your own risk and you understand that your information may be collected and used by others.

Please remember that protection of your privacy begins with you. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any password you use to register, and you should always be careful and responsible whenever disclosing information online.

This website has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. When you place orders we use a secure server, which encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. All of the customer data we collect is similarly protected against unauthorized access.

_Granta_ will not share your personal information with third parties unless you have consented to the disclosure or the disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process, (2) protect and defend our rights and property, (3) protect our customers or users from misuse or unauthorized use of the _Granta_ website or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our customers or the public.

**Links to other websites**  
The _Granta_ website may contain links to other sites, operated by third parties, that we think may be of interest to you. _Granta_ encourages third parties to follow appropriate privacy standards and policies, but is not responsible for the actions of those third parties, the content of their websites or any practices they may follow.

_**How do I accept this privacy statement?**_

By using the _Granta_ site and services, you signify your acceptance of this privacy statement. If you do not agree or are not comfortable with any policy described in this privacy statement, your only remedy is to discontinue use of the _Granta site_. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time. Your continued use of any portion of the _Granta_ site following notification or posting of such changes, will constitute your acceptance of those changes. If you have questions or concerns about our specific policies, please send an email to info@granta.com.
